# VISHAL GANGWAR

## **ACHIEVEMENTS**

#### Award for best Employee

Received "Best Employee of the Year" award. Acknowledged for dedication, contributing to development improvement. Committed to excellence and effective collaboration in the current organization.

## **STRENGTHS**

- Excellent Debugging
   Skills Proficient in identifying and resolving complex software issues
- Quick Learner
   Adaptable and able to quickly grasp new concepts and technologies.

## **SKILLS**

React.js · Redux Next.js·HTML5 · CSS3 · Typescript · Java · OOPs · SpringBoot · MySql · JIRA · Git

#### **EDUCATION**

Bachelor's Degree in Information Technology

Kamla Nehru Institute of Technology

07/2017 - 07/2021 Sultanpur, U.P

## Software Developer

📞 8840216454 🖾 vishalgangwar094@gmail.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/vishal-gangwar-a6aa5b186/

https://gangwar2944.github.io/my\_portfolio

https://github.com/gangwar2944 P Noida

#### **SUMMARY**

Motivated web developer with 3 years of experience and a strong skill in React.js, Redux,Next.js ,TypeScript, HTML, CSS,Java,SpringBoot and MySql.seeking a position that leverages my skills and passion for programming in a remote and distributed environment.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## React.js Developer

08/2022 - Present

## Rawcubes India Private Limited, Noida

Noida

- · Contributed to web development projects using React.js and Typescript.
- Migrated Syncfusion components to Material UI components for the entire website as part of a team effort.
- Used Redux for state management and made API calls using Thunk middleware
- Collaborated with the team to build interactive user interfaces and improve user experiences.
- Integrated third-party APIs to enhance application functionality and data retrieval.
- Participated in debugging and troubleshooting to enhance application performance
- Actively contributed to peer code reviews to ensure high-quality standards
- Refactored existing code to increase efficiency and reduce redundancy.

## Junior Software Engineer

08/2021 - 07/2022

## **Brain Technosys Pvt Ltd**

Noida

- Contributed to all phases of the development lifecycle, from design to writing and developing, mostly on the backend.
- Developed APIs to return data for the dashboard.
- Skilled in CRUD operations, proficiently implementing Create, Read, Update, and Delete functionalities to manage data effectively in applications.

#### **PROJECTS**

## **iDataOps**

11/2023 - 2024

Machine Monitoring Software :-Overcome downtime challenges by tracking machine operations in real-time, utilizing advanced OEE, and enhance overall operational efficiency.

## qDataOps

08/2022 - 11/2023

Introducing Quality Console, a centralized Quality Control Command Center for realtime monitoring of manufacturing quality checks. Automate data quality checks, streamline inspection processes, and empower decision makers with data-driven dashboards. Elevate your quality management system and make informed, strategic decisions for enhanced business performance.

## Data Asset Management System

08/2021 - 07/2022

Developed a web app to track assets and employees, manage attendance, and maintain vendor and office information.

Utilized Technologies:- Spring Boot, React.js, and MySQL.